Stephen Price

Software Engineer

Stephen Price Intriago

512-998-5903

1003 Justin Lane Austin, TX 78757

stellopricint@gmail.com

stephenlprice.github.io/portfolio

in linkedin.com/in/slprice

github.com/stephenlprice

public.tableau.com/profile/stprice

stackoverflow.com

Web Developer with 3+ years of experience in software solutions consulting. Experienced in collaborating with developers, product managers, and software architects. Familiar with agile development and version control (Github, Gitlab, Bitbucket), including tools such as Product Board and ZenHub. A confident presenter and teacher that can simplify complicated concepts to obtain actionable results.

Always stood out as a technical counterpart to customer-facing teams and acquired most of the skillset through self-education. Specialized in embedding data visualizations into customer apps at Tableau Software. Learned about API design and OpenAPI from subject matter experts at Stoplight.io. Attended the Coding Boot Camp at the University of Texas.

Technical Skills

Languages: JavaScript ES6+, HTML5, CSS3, Python, R, SQL

Tools & Frameworks: Node.js, React.js, Express.js, Django, Wagtail CMS, Docker, Spectral (OpenAPI validation), Prism (API mocking and contract testing), Anaconda

Applications: MySQL, MongoDB, Github, Gitlab, Bitbucket, Tableau Desktop, Tableau Server, Stoplight Studio, Zenhub, Product Board, Postman, Swaggerhub, AWS, GCP, Azure, Heroku

Standards: OpenAPIv2, OpenAPIv3

Projects

Marvel Basement / Role: Project Manager, JavaScript, and AJAX January 2021

A website that searches for characters from the Marvel universe displaying metadata and descriptions along with animated gifs.

Technologies:

Marvel API, Giphy API, Materialize, Google Fonts, jQuery, Font Awesome, iFramely, Stoplight, APIMatic, OpenAPI Specification

Project: https://github.com/API-Guild/marvel-basement
Repository: https://api-guild.github.io/marvel-basement

Marduk / Role: Sole Author

January 2021

A weather forecasting website using the OpenWeather API to obtain current weather conditions and 5-day forecasts. Images are obtained from the Unsplash API.

Technologies:

<u>OpenWeather API, Unsplash API, Bootstrap, jQuery, Font Awesome, Day.is</u>

Project: https://github.com/stephenlprice/marduk
Repository: https://stephenlprice.github.io/marduk

Memento Mori / Role: Sole Author

December 2020

A workday scheduler that highlight hours past, present, and future to help plan your workday. Any unsaved events will be cleared to keep the calendar nice and organized.

Technologies:

Bootstrap, ¡Query, Font Awesome, Day.js

Project: https://github.com/stephenlprice/memento-mori
Repository: https://stephenlprice.github.io/memento-mori

Experience

Stoplight.io / Solutions Consultant

December 2019 - December 2020 | Austin, Texas

- Enabled end-users in the use of Stoplight Studio for API design as well as in the management of API portals & design environments
- Supported on-premise POCs deployed via Docker
- Developed resources for demonstrations and development of growing sales and presales teams
- Point of contact explaining roadmap updates to customers and sharing feedback with Product Management

Tableau Software / Senior Product Consultant

July 2017 - December 2019 | Austin, Texas

- Expert in the Tableau Platform for cloud-hosted and on-premise data visualization, data preparation, and analysis
- Specialized in embedding dashboards and data visualizations into custom applications
- Confident presenter and educator presented webinars and training sessions at Tableau Conference
- Familiar with Python and R for data analysis and to extend the capabilities of Tableau products

Hilong / Marketing Coordinator

- Technical role on the steel tubular sales team.
- Contract Administrator for 4 different "just in time" supply chain contracts.
- Developed a system for managing tubular imports, deliveries, and stock levels used to forecast material requirements under the "just in time" model.
- Responsible for tender processes with state-owned and multinational corporations.
- Responsible for the successful evaluation of our logistics center and business segment under the API Q2 and API 5CT standards.
- Successful introduction of Baosteel Premium Connection tubing to the Ecuadorian market.

Atlanta Institute of Language / Spanish Instructor

March 2014 - July 2014 | Atlanta, Georgia

 Teach Spanish language skills, culture, and history to students in group or private lessons that take place either offsite or in classroom settings.

Alma College / Spanish Teaching Assistant

September 2012 - April 2013 | Alma, Michigan

• Teaching assistance in the Spanish Language Department during college.

Education

University of Texas / Certificate: Full Stack Web Development December 2020 - March 2021 | Austin, Texas

12 week, immersive program covering the following subjects: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, MERN stack, Database Theory, MongoDB, MySQL, Heroku, Git, and Quality Assurance. An understanding of computer science applied to JavaScript.

Alma College / Bachelor of Arts: Business Administration 2009 - 2013 | Alma, Michigan 3.2 GPA

Hutong School / Certificate: Intermediate Mandarin Chinese 2012 | Beijing, China / Shanghai, China